Many times it has happened that we have taken health
insurance.  But even after that
our claim will not be passed.
Because our expenses are
OPD.  OPD means Outpatient
Department.  This means that the applications
which the insurance company does not cover and
if it covers them then it covers them as per a limit.
So today we will talk about
four such best health insurance policies
in which you will get OPD cover.  So
you should watch the video till the end.  So if
you like the video then please like, share and
subscribe.  So let's start the video directly here.
So now let us see
which are the four plans in which your
OPD expenses can be covered.  This means that
your hospitalization expenses, which
are the expenses inside the hospital, and the
OPD expenses outside the hospital can also be
covered.  The first is Niba's Well Consult
Rider.  The second is HDFC Ago's Optima Well
Bean.  The third is ICCI Lambar's B Fit
Rider.  The fourth is Star Health Insurance's
Outpatient Care, which I have told you about the first three
companies and the names I have told you in them are
riders, you
can include them in your policy to
cover OPD. The fourth option of the policy that I
told you is Star Health's
Outpatient Care, which is an OPD plan itself,
which is a separate stand-around health
insurance policy.  So now let us talk about
what is covered in the Well Consult Rider of NIVAPA.  The first thing is the
Niv Well Consult Rider.
What will be our first point covered in this?
TERI consultation is covered.  Physical
consultation is covered.  IST test
is covered.  Pharmacy is covered.  Gym membership
is covered.  Visit is covered.  WeekWise
is AI fitness coaching for adults.  Right and
nutrition and emotional wellness services
covered.  And whatever I have
told you, there is a limit to all these things.  So
whatever it is, of course there will definitely be a limit.
So let us also see up to what amount it is covered.
Now let's talk about HDFC's
Octo Well Being Right, what
is covered in it?  Unlimited teleconsultation
is covered.  Unlimited OPD Consultation Covered
Unlimited Psychology e Consultation Covered.
Unlimited life fitness coaching
is covered.  Meaning, you will get sessions, consultation and
guidance for diet and nutrition from
dietitian and nutrition at up to 50%
discount at Lab S A.
You will get up to 20% discount
on medicines as there is home sample telephony.  These are
all the things that are covered inside HVSC's Optima
Bell B Rider.  Now let's talk
about the third ICIC Lambd which is the B fit
rider. Options available in the B fit rider of this ICIC LBD
are from A to F.
You
can design your policy as per your convenience.
You can avail the OPD feature.  Now
what are the reasons behind it?  I want to give you an OPD
consultation.  Diagnostic test pharmacy
cover psychotherapy session.  There is a consultation.
There are counselling sessions with psychologists.
Nutrition and wellness consultations are covered.
Preventative care is covered being coach
covered.  These are all the things that
you get inside the ICC LBA B Filled Rider.  Plus
there is also a help program in ICICI's
Beef Driver which you
can use and you can get a discount on removal.
Now let's talk about Star Health
Insurance. The last company Star Health
Insurance has launched is an
OPD plan. Firstly, what is covered in it is
your OPD consultation in network
facility. Second, Ayush consultancy means
consultation, tele-consultation is covered. Physical
consultation is covered. Diagnostic test is
covered. Physiotherapy,
pharmacy, dental treatment or thoracic
treatment is covered. All these things are covered in
your Star's outpatient care plan. So, the
first company which I
told you about was Bupa's Bell Being Rider. Right
now you can take this rider
with nvba care black because a
rider is available in it only.  Talking about HLFC,
I have told you about Optimum Well Being
Rider.
You can take this rider with both Optimal Restore and Optimal Secure Black.  In the ICICI
Lambd's Defeat Rider, this
rider is the Elevate Plan and there is also the
E Advantage Plan.
You can take this rider with both these plans.  The
second plan was Your Health
Advantage.  The first was your Elevate, the second was
Health Advantage.  You can add this rider with them.
So the minimum age will be the
same as in the basic plans,
like right now we are talking about Nimopa.   If we
talk about HFC or if we first
talk about Nimopa, then the minimum
age in it is 18 years and the maximum is
65. If we talk about HBFC, the minimum age is 18
years and there is no maximum age.
ICICI is long, the minimum age is
six years and the maximum is 65 years.
In Star's policy, your minimum
age is 18 years and maximum is 50 years.  Now let's
talk about how you can claim it.
You have taken the policy and a claim comes
in the future, then how will you claim at that time
?  So in that plan of Bupa,
you can
take care of both cashless and reimbursement methods.
How to go cashless?  You can download their app and
talk to your doctor
, discuss, consult and
book from there.  So you will get all these
options for cashless claim below.  The
second is your physical if
you want to meet the bill, meaning
with the doctor.  Ok?  So you want to get the physical bill etc.
from the doctor, so for that you will go to the doctor.
You will pay the bill yourself.
One thing to keep in mind here is that the
reimbursement claim you will have will be given to you along with 20% pay.
Meaning, whatever amount you are
showing to the company, whatever bill you are showing to the
company, the company will deduct 20% and
give you the money.  Whatever claim you can make in HDFC Labs,
you can do it cashless.
Cashless: Whether you are online or offline,
your facility will
remain cashless.  This means that when you go to make a claim,
it will go through their panel only.  You don't have to
give anything.  If you book from here, there will be
no reimbursement.  It will be booked from here.
Simple is cashless.  If
we talk about ICICI LBD, it is also cashless and
perhaps health insurance is also
cashless.  To make a claim in Nivpa
for OPD, you have to download the Nivpa app.
Nivpa comes with the name of Health App.
If you want to
claim for OD in HDFC Ago, then you have to
download the app.  HDFC Ago HR App Thirdly,
if you want to make a claim for ICICI LB, then
you have to download the app.  IL Take Care
App IL means ICIC L, the fourth company is your Star
Health, as you have to claim OT Care,
then in that Star Health App, all these four,
you can claim OPD, to
claim OPD you will have to download this app,
so now let's talk about
how much amount we can claim,
how much OPD we can do, how much online
consultation we can do, how much physical
consultation we can do, let's see what is the limit on which things, so the
first thing in Niva Bufa is your TERI consultation is
unlimited.  Secondly, if we talk about physical concussion,
it is yours up to ₹1000.
You will get physical consultation up to ₹10,000.   The
third thing you need is diagnostic tests.   This is
also your
diagnostic test worth up to ₹10,000.  Whatever
diagnostic tests are there, they will be covered.
Talking about pharmacy,
your pharmacy is covered up to ₹2500.
Your pharmacy also up to ₹2500.
Talking about gym membership for two weeks
for adults.  Along with this, gym membership is available for two
weeks per adult.
You can avail AIB Fitness Coaching Diet & Nutrition Unlimited.
You can take 10 emotional wellness sessions
within a year.  Whatever I have told you,
you can get it within this year.  Ok?
And if you have a family policy up to the limit, then as
I told you,
you will get up to ₹2500 for pharmacy.
Whether it is a family policy or an
individual policy.  Now let's talk about
HDFCO Wellbeing Write Up.  The first thing you get is
unlimited tele consultation with
specialists and super special along with
general practitioners.  You are
getting this facility unlimitedly.  Second,
unlimited OPD consultation with general
practice.  Thirdly, unlimited psychological
counselling free of cost.  Fourth Unlimited
Live Fitness Sessions by Experts for Yoga.
Zamba Pylex.  What is your unlimited after this
?  Unlimited e-consultations and
guidance on diet and nutrition from
dietitians and nutritionists.  Last
three points offer up to 50% off on lab
tests and health checkup packages plus 20%
discount on medicines.
Free home sample collection irrespective of
card value.  Now let's talk about ICIC
Lambar's Bfit ridership.  So in this
I told you earlier that there are options from A to F.
You
can add whatever things you want in it.  But let us
know what exactly we are getting in it.  Now see, if you
choose option A of ICICI LB here, then
here you will get 12 teleconsultations and
six e-counselling.  Dietitian and
Nutrition E concentration will get you six.
So you will get these things.  An option if you
choose ICIC LB's B Fit RideMe.   If you
look at option B, you will get routine
diagnostic cover and minor procedure cover up
to ₹1000. In option B, pharmacy
cover up to ₹1000, the remaining three options are tele
consultation, e counselling, guide and that is
sale. After that, if we talk about
C point here, then here at C point your
six will be covered, outpatient consultations will be
covered, routine diagnostic cover and
minor procedure cover will be available to you up to ₹1000,
okay, and pharmacy cover up to ₹1000. Here
you are also getting geotherapy session.
In C, you will get up to six, the rest of the telecons
are covered, 12 e counselling six, diet and
nutrition and e conservation six
are covered.  Preventative care has you covered for up to six.
Preventive care: Yes, this is also covered for
you.  Now these four points below,
as you can see, I have
not told you yet, they are applicable to everyone.  Well
beam program ambulance assistant value
with service this is your rank covered in all a b c d a b
c d e or sub.  But the
health management program is
not covered in your A option.
In everything else, it will be your option.   It
depends on you.  Rest of the
points are written in D as well.  It is
also written in E.  It is
also written in F.  So
what are you getting from your way of looking at things this way
?  Which option do you have to choose?
If you are taking a Bewad Rider with SSC number, then
which
options will be best for you as per
your convenience according to OPD.
So whatever feels right to you, choose whatever
feels right to you first.  Here
you just have to keep in mind that you have to check
according to your city and your pin code
whether the things that I am buying are
available in my pin code or
not.  If you have to see it first, there will be many
things many times.  Sometimes something will not happen.
You have to check that thing also.  Whatever
tests etc. you are getting here,
you have to do them through this app.
IL Take Care World
through the app I put you on.  If
you think that I talk to my doctor and pay the
bill and show it to him, then it will
not be covered.  Now let's talk
about Star Health Insurance's outpatient plan.
Some screenshots are available here.
25000 to 50000, 75000 and 1 lakh variants
are Silver Gold and Platinum, it is important to keep in mind
that
you can choose from Silver Gold and Platinum among the options that I told you
and the inpatient one
is not covered.  This is an OPD plan,
not a proper inpatient plan.  The remaining three remain
inpatient, meaning the health
insurance process of getting
admitted to the hospital, all those expenses
are covered by it.  That is basic, so
along with insurance, the names that I told you like In-
Befit etc. or Well Being, Well Being
etc., all of them are riders, so in that
both your OPD and health were covered, this is just proper
insurance, this is
an OPD plan, so there is no insurance in it, there is
no expense inside the hospital, this is
only the OPD expenses, that means
OPD is covered up to Rs 25000, up to Rs 75000, up to Rs 50000, up to Rs
1 lakh, in what way is your OPD
covered, so as I told you
what is covered in four health shops, OPD
consultation, tele consultation, you can give a list,
all the things are
included in this policy of yours.  All these things that you are
seeing will be
covered for you up to Rs 25000, 50000, 75000 or 1 lakh.
Now let's talk about the waiting period. There is a
waiting period inside the OPD also.   The
initial waiting period is 30 days.  This means that for the
first 30 days you cannot use the OPD plan
or you cannot avail the benefits of OPD feeders.
If you have to consult a slow growing illness, it will take you two
years.  The waiting period for pre-existing disease, the
waiting period of your policy which has been mentioned, will be of
3 years
ex GST. Within Optimus Secure itself,
your waiting period is of 3 years, which means
if you have to make any OPD claim for pre-existing disease, then it will take
three years.
After three years, your IC plan
is also of three years or whatever your waiting
period will be, your waiting period will be according to that.
What is the difference between the three plans - Silver, Platinum and Gold.
If you take Silver plan, then there is a
waiting period of 48 months, which means four years. If you
take Gold plan, then there is a
waiting period of 2 years in it, 24 months. If
you add Plating Up, then there is a
waiting period of 12 months, which means one
year. I am telling you this waiting period,
3 years, four years.
This is for your OPD in all the four companies. If you have
this problem already and want to make
any claim in OPD, then you can do that in these  You
can claim after three or four years or after two years on
the plan I told you about.  So
guys, these were four such OPD plans
in health insurance which you
can choose as per your convenience and budget.
I told you about four companies, ICIC, HDFC,
NVPA and ST.  So guys this was today's video.
I hope you found the information I gave you
valuable and understandable.  And if you have
n't subscribed to my channel yet, please
subscribe to it.  See you
in the next video like this.  Till then take care.
Bye-bye goodbye.  And
bye-bye Jai Hind.